Fred D. Warren Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Fred D. Warren Papers.
1899-1917
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Warren, Fred D.
.25 linear feet.
Managing editor of Appeal to Reason.
MSS19760003
Biography
Managing editor of Appeal to Reason.
Scope and Content
The collection is, presumably, only a portion of the business correspondence of Fred D. Warren, the managing editor of the Appeal to Reason, a Socialist weekly with the largest circulation in the United States. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1910- 1914. The correspondence includes letters between Warren and his business partner, Upton Sinclair, and their dispute over the publication rights to Sinclair's play, The Millenium. Also included is correspondence between Warren and Eugene V. Debs, the perennial presidential candidate of the Socialist Party. Debs served as a contributing editor of the Appeal to Reason. These letters clearly reflect Debs' opinions of people and events associated with the Socialist Party, including the Barnes Affair, the campaign of 1912, Victor Berger and Morris Hillquit.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to alternative lifestyles, politics and publications. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Warren, Fred D., 1872 or 3-1959.
Organizations:
Socialist Party (U.S.)
Subjects:
Editors—United States.; United States—Politics and government—1909-1913.; United States—Politics and government—1913-1921.
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Occupations:
Editor.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Mr. Warren's son in 1976.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Incoming Correspondence, undated, 1899-1917
  - Debs, Eugene V., 1910 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Debs, Eugene V., 1912-1917 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets, 1899, 1912 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Debs, Katherine M., 1910 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Debs, Theodore, 1910, 1912 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Goebel, George, 1914 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1909-1915 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
- Series II: Outgoing Correspondence, 1915
  - Wayland, Walter H., 1915 (Box 1:, Folder 8)